Rory Harder

E-mail rory.harder@mail.utoronto.ca url https://www.roryharder.com

Address Philosophy Department, 170 St. George St., Toronto, ON, Canada M5R 2M8

AOS Philosophy of Language, Philosophy of Mind

AOC Epistemology (including formal), Logic

Academic Employment

2021–2022 Postdoctoral Fellow, University of Toronto 2019–2021 Part Time Lecturer, Rutgers University

Education

GRADUATE

2015–2022 PHD in Philosophy, University of Toronto

Dissertation Title: Joint Action and Communication, With a Focus on Demonstratives

Co-Supervisors: Imogen Dickie and Nate Charlow VISITING STUDENT in Linguistics, Rutgers University

Host Supervisor: Simon Charlow

Undergraduate

2012–2015 BA (Hons) with High Distinction in Philosophy (Specialist) and History and Philosophy

of Science and Technology (Minor), University of Toronto

2011–2012 Trent University 2010–2011 Fleming College

2019

Papers

PEER-REVIEWED JOURNAL ARTICLES

Accepted Joint Attention and Communication

Inquiry: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Philosophy

Under Review

[A paper on the formal semantics of demonstratives] Revised and Resubmitted at Linguistics & Philosophy
[A paper on demonstratives and joint attention]
[A paper on the pragmatics of demonstratives]

Under Preparation

The Simple Theory of Joint Action A Tale of Two Theories of Mind A Heimian Solution to a Puzzle of Context-Sensitivity

Presentations

Refereed

Joint Attention: The Window Into Other Minds? 2021 American Philosophical Association (APA) Pacific Division Meeting (Symposium) Joint Attention and Communication Mutual Knowledge 40 Workshop A Puzzle About Demonstrative Understanding The Seventh International Conference on Philosophy of Language and Linguistics Perspectives in Demonstrative Semantics 2020 WeSSLLI Student Session; Szklarska Poreba Workshop The Affiliative Conception of Sense 2019 Communication, Context, Conversation Workshop Clearing up Clouds APA Pacific Division Meeting (Colloquium) Clearing up Clouds 2018 Context, Cognition, and Communication Conference Inferences and Neutrality of the Deliberative Ought 2017 APA Pacific Division Meeting (Colloquium); Canadian Philosophical Association Meeting

INVITED

The Grammar of Reference
New York Philosophy of Language Workshop

Rory Harder 2

Teaching

Course In	NSTRUCTORSHIPS	AT RUTGERS	UNIVERSITY
-----------	----------------	------------	------------

Introduction to Formal Reasoning and Decision Making (1st year, Online)
Introduction to Formal Reasoning and Decision Making (1st year)

Course Instructorships at the University of Toronto

Special Topics in Philosophy: Frege's Puzzle (3rd year, Online)
Issues in Philosophy of Mind: Perception and Conception (3rd year)

OTHER

Super-TA for the Socrates Project (Supervising Undergraduate TAs, University of Toronto)
Philosophy Don (Tutor and Residence Assistant, Trinity College, University of Toronto)

TEACHING ASSISTANTSHIPS AT THE UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

Ancient Philosophy (2nd year), 17th- and 18th-Century Philosophy (2nd year), Introduction to Philosophy (1st year), Knowledge and Reality (2nd year), Probability and Inductive Logic (2nd year), Introduction to Symbolic Logic (2nd year, online)

Scholarships & Awards

2020–2021 Doctoral Completion Award (\$14,859)

Merit-based award for graduate students at the University of Toronto.

2019–2020 Ontario Graduate Scholarship (\$15,000)

Merit-based scholarship for graduate students at public universities in Ontario.

SSHRC CGS Michael Smith Foreign Study Supplement (\$6,000)

Awarded to 125 applicants, Canadian graduate students in social sciences and humanities.

2016–2019 SSHRC Joseph-Armand Bombardier CGS Doctoral Scholarship (\$105,000)

Awarded to 22% of applicants, Canadian graduate students in social sciences and humanities.

Professional Activity

2022 CHAIR at APA Pacific Division Meeting

2020 Graduate Student Coordinator for Institutional Strategic Initiative in Language and

Cognition, University of Toronto

Referee and Commentator for Philosophy Graduate Student Conference, University of

Toronto

Rory Harder

Graduate Coursework

History Seminar in Plato; Consciousness Then and Now

Ethics Controlling Attitudes; Valuing, Narrative, and What Matters in Life

LEMM Perception and Epistemology; Vagueness; Mind or World; Semantics for Philosophy; For-

mal Epistemology; Metasemantics; Frege; Deductive and Inductive Logic

Linguistics Topics in Event Semantics; Introduction to Syntactic Theory

Dissertation

Title Joint Action and Communication, With a Focus on Demonstratives

Summary

My dissertation develops a view of human communication according to which it is the joint activity of making sense of one another, as fellow agents, in virtue of our actions. I consider the relationship between communication and joint attention in order to show how my view provides a superior successor to orthodox Griceanism. I also motivate my view by using it to explain how there can be successful communication, involving a demonstrative, despite the interlocutors not settling on one or another object as referent. Finally, I address a challenge, which arises for any Gricean view of communication, of explaining what is special about linguistic communication. My answer is based on a formal semantics for demonstratives and related expressions, and draws upon the tradition of dynamic semantics.

References

Research IMOGEN DICKIE, Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: imogen.dickie@utoronto.ca

NATE CHARLOW, Associate Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: nate.charlow@utoronto.ca

PHILIP KREMER, Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: philip.kremer@utoronto.ca

Teaching RACHEL BARNEY, Professor, Department of Philosophy, University of Toronto

Contact: rachel.barney@utoronto.ca

Rory Harder 4